<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Protobuf Editions on Protocol Buffers Documentation</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/editions/</link><description>Recent content in Protobuf Editions on Protocol Buffers Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://protobuf.dev/editions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Protobuf Editions Overview</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/editions/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/editions/overview/</guid><description>Protobuf Editions replace the proto2 and proto3 designations that we have used for Protocol Buffers. Instead of adding syntax = &amp;quot;proto2&amp;quot; or syntax = &amp;quot;proto3&amp;quot; at the top of proto definition files, you use an edition number, such as edition = &amp;quot;2024&amp;quot;, to specify the default behaviors your file will have. Editions enable the language to evolve incrementally over time.
Instead of the hardcoded behaviors that older versions have had, editions represent a collection of features with a default value (behavior) per feature.</description></item><item><title>Feature Settings for Editions</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/editions/features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/editions/features/</guid><description>This topic provides an overview of the features that are included in the released edition versions. Subsequent editions&amp;rsquo; features will be added to this topic. We announce new editions in the News section.
Before configuring feature settings in your new schema definition content, make sure you understand why you are using them. Avoid cargo-culting with features.
Prototiller Prototiller is a command-line tool that updates proto schema configuration files between syntax versions and editions.</description></item><item><title>Implementing Editions Support</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/editions/implementation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/editions/implementation/</guid><description>This topic explains how to implement editions in new runtimes and generators.
Overview Edition 2023 The first edition released is Edition 2023, which is designed to unify proto2 and proto3 syntax. The features we’ve added to cover the difference in behaviors are detailed in Feature Settings for Editions.
Feature Definition In addition to supporting editions and the global features we&amp;rsquo;ve defined, you may want to define your own features to leverage the infrastructure.</description></item></channel></rss>