<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorials on Protocol Buffers Documentation</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorials on Protocol Buffers Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Protocol Buffer Basics: C++</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/cpptutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/cpptutorial/</guid><description>This tutorial provides a basic C++ programmers introduction to working with protocol buffers. By walking through creating a simple example application, it shows you how to
Define message formats in a .proto file. Use the protocol buffer compiler. Use the C++ protocol buffer API to write and read messages. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive guide to using protocol buffers in C++. For more detailed reference information, see the Protocol Buffer Language Guide, the C++ API Reference, the C++ Generated Code Guide, and the Encoding Reference.</description></item><item><title>Protocol Buffer Basics: C#</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/csharptutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/csharptutorial/</guid><description>This tutorial provides a basic C# programmer&amp;rsquo;s introduction to working with protocol buffers, using the proto3 version of the protocol buffers language. By walking through creating a simple example application, it shows you how to
Define message formats in a .proto file. Use the protocol buffer compiler. Use the C# protocol buffer API to write and read messages. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive guide to using protocol buffers in C#. For more detailed reference information, see the Protocol Buffer Language Guide, the C# API Reference, the C# Generated Code Guide, and the Encoding Reference.</description></item><item><title>Protocol Buffer Basics: Dart</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/darttutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/darttutorial/</guid><description>This tutorial provides a basic Dart programmer&amp;rsquo;s introduction to working with protocol buffers, using the proto3 version of the protocol buffers language. By walking through creating a simple example application, it shows you how to
Define message formats in a .proto file. Use the protocol buffer compiler. Use the Dart protocol buffer API to write and read messages. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive guide to using protocol buffers in Dart . For more detailed reference information, see the Protocol Buffer Language Guide, the Dart Language Tour, the Dart API Reference, the Dart Generated Code Guide, and the Encoding Reference.</description></item><item><title>Protocol Buffer Basics: Go</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/gotutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/gotutorial/</guid><description>This tutorial provides a basic Go programmer&amp;rsquo;s introduction to working with protocol buffers, using the proto3 version of the protocol buffers language. By walking through creating a simple example application, it shows you how to
Define message formats in a .proto file. Use the protocol buffer compiler. Use the Go protocol buffer API to write and read messages. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive guide to using protocol buffers in Go. For more detailed reference information, see the Protocol Buffer Language Guide, the Go API Reference, the Go Generated Code Guide, and the Encoding Reference.</description></item><item><title>Protocol Buffer Basics: Java</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/javatutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/javatutorial/</guid><description>This tutorial provides a basic Java programmer&amp;rsquo;s introduction to working with protocol buffers. By walking through creating a simple example application, it shows you how to
Define message formats in a .proto file. Use the protocol buffer compiler. Use the Java protocol buffer API to write and read messages. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive guide to using protocol buffers in Java. For more detailed reference information, see the Protocol Buffer Language Guide (proto2), the Protocol Buffer Language Guide (proto3), the Java API Reference, the Java Generated Code Guide, and the Encoding Reference.</description></item><item><title>Protocol Buffer Basics: Kotlin</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/kotlintutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/kotlintutorial/</guid><description>This tutorial provides a basic Kotlin programmer&amp;rsquo;s introduction to working with protocol buffers, using the proto3 version of the protocol buffers language. By walking through creating a simple example application, it shows you how to
Define message formats in a .proto file. Use the protocol buffer compiler. Use the Kotlin protocol buffer API to write and read messages. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive guide to using protocol buffers in Kotlin. For more detailed reference information, see the Protocol Buffer Language Guide, the Kotlin API Reference, the Kotlin Generated Code Guide, and the Encoding Reference.</description></item><item><title>Protocol Buffer Basics: Python</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/pythontutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/getting-started/pythontutorial/</guid><description>This tutorial provides a basic Python programmer&amp;rsquo;s introduction to working with protocol buffers. By walking through creating a simple example application, it shows you how to
Define message formats in a .proto file. Use the protocol buffer compiler. Use the Python protocol buffer API to write and read messages. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a comprehensive guide to using protocol buffers in Python. For more detailed reference information, see the Protocol Buffer Language Guide (proto2), the Protocol Buffer Language Guide (proto3), the Python API Reference, the Python Generated Code Guide, and the Encoding Reference.</description></item></channel></rss>