<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Go Reference on Protocol Buffers Documentation</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/</link><description>Recent content in Go Reference on Protocol Buffers Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Go Generated Code Guide (Open)</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/go-generated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/go-generated/</guid><description>Any differences between proto2, proto3, and editions generated code are highlighted - note that these differences are in the generated code as described in this document, not the base API, which are the same in both versions. You should read the proto2 language guide, proto3 language guide, or editions language guide before reading this document.
Note You are looking at documentation for the old generated code API (Open Struct API). See Go Generated Code (Opaque) for the corresponding documentation of the (new) Opaque API.</description></item><item><title>Go Generated Code Guide (Opaque)</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/go-generated-opaque/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/go-generated-opaque/</guid><description>Any differences between proto2 and proto3 generated code are highlighted - note that these differences are in the generated code as described in this document, not the base API, which are the same in both versions. You should read the proto2 language guide and/or the proto3 language guide before reading this document.
Note You are looking at documentation for the Opaque API, which is the current version. If you are working with .</description></item><item><title>Go FAQ</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/faq/</guid><description>Versions What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between github.com/golang/protobuf and google.golang.org/protobuf? The github.com/golang/protobuf module is the original Go protocol buffer API.
The google.golang.org/protobuf module is an updated version of this API designed for simplicity, ease of use, and safety. The flagship features of the updated API are support for reflection and a separation of the user-facing API from the underlying implementation.
We recommend that you use google.golang.org/protobuf in new code.
Version v1.4.0 and higher of github.</description></item><item><title>Go Size Semantics</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/size/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/size/</guid><description>The proto.Size function returns the size in bytes of the wire-format encoding of a proto.Message by traversing all its fields (including submessages).
In particular, it returns the size of how Go Protobuf will encode the message.
A note on Protobuf Editions With Protobuf Editions, .proto files can enable features that change serialization behavior. This can affect the value returned by proto.Size. For example, setting features.field_presence = IMPLICIT will cause scalar fields that are set to their defaults to not be serialized, and therefore don&amp;rsquo;t contribute to the size of the message.</description></item><item><title>Go API</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/api-docs-link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/api-docs-link/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Go Opaque API Migration</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/opaque-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/opaque-migration/</guid><description>The Opaque API is the latest version of the Protocol Buffers implementation for the Go programming language. The old version is now called Open Struct API. See the Go Protobuf: Releasing the Opaque API blog post for an introduction.
The migration to the Opaque API happens incrementally, on a per-proto-message or per-.proto-file basis, by setting the api_level feature to one of its possible values:
API_OPEN selects the Open Struct API. This was backported into edition 2023, so older versions of the Go plugin may not honor it.</description></item><item><title>Go Opaque API: Manual Migration</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/opaque-migration-manual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/opaque-migration-manual/</guid><description>The Opaque API is the latest version of the Protocol Buffers implementation for the Go programming language. The old version is now called Open Struct API. See the Go Protobuf: Releasing the Opaque API blog post for an introduction.
This is a user guide for migrating Go Protobuf usages from the older Open Struct API to the new Opaque API.
Warning You are looking at the manual migration guide. Typically you’re better off using the open2opaque tool to automate the migration.</description></item><item><title>Go Opaque API FAQ</title><link>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/opaque-faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://protobuf.dev/reference/go/opaque-faq/</guid><description>The Opaque API is the latest version of the Protocol Buffers implementation for the Go programming language. The old version is now called Open Struct API. See the Go Protobuf: The new Opaque API blog post for an introduction.
This FAQ answers common questions about the new API and the migration process.
Which API Should I Use When Creating a New .proto File? We recommend you select the Opaque API for new development.</description></item></channel></rss>